Welcome to intro to data analysis.
مرحبًا بك في مقدمة عن تحليل البيانات.
My name is Juno, and I'll be your instructor for this course.
أُدعى جونو وسأكون معلمكم خلال هذه الدورة التدريبية.
A data analyst, is someone who uses data to answer questions,
محلل البيانات، هو شخص يستخدم البيانات للإجابة على الأسئلة،
and that's exactly what you'll be doing here.
وهذا هو بالضبط ما ستفعله هنا.
You'll tackle questions like,
سوف تعالج أسئلة مثل،
what characteristics make a tumor more likely to be cancerous?
ما الخصائص التي تجعل الورم أكثر عرضة للسرطان؟
Or how much of car models improved since 2008 and which vehicles improved the most?
أو إلى أي مدى تحسنت طرز السيارات منذ عام 2008 وما السيارات التي تحسنت أكثر؟
Or how does wine quality vary by type,
أو كيف تختلف جودة النبيذ حسب النوع
alcohol content, sugar, acidity level and much more?
ومحتوى الكحول والسكر ومستوى الحموضة وأكثر من ذلك بكثير؟
You'll also be introduced to some valuable libraries for data analysis in Python.
سيتم أيضًا تعريفك ببعض المكتبات القيّمة لتحليل البيانات في Python.
Specifically, Numpy, Pandas and Matplotlib.
وبالأخص، Numpy وPandas وMatplotlib.
The aim of this course,
يتمثل الهدف من هذه الدورة في
is to give you the tools and confidence to analyze data with Python and
تزويدك بالأدوات والثقة لتحليل البيانات مع Python
experience going through the steps of the data analysis process on real data sets.
وتجربة المرور عبر خطوات عملية تحليل البيانات على مجموعات البيانات الحقيقية.
There are additional Udacity courses that dive deeply into each step
هناك دورات إضافية من Udacity تغوص بعمق في كل خطوة
of the process so don't worry if you don't get everything right away.
من العملية، لذلك لا تقلق إذا كنت لا تحصل على كل شيء على الفور.
This course doesn't require any previous experience with data analysis,
لا تتطلب هذه الدورة التدريبية أي خبرة سابقة في تحليل البيانات،
but you should already be comfortable programming in Python.
ولكن يجب أن تكون بالفعل تشعر بالارتياح للبرمجة في Python.
You should be familiar with things like, loops,
يجب أن تكون على دراية بأشياء مثل الحلقات
functions, classes, dictionaries, lists and data types.
والدوال والفئات والقواميس والقوائم وأنواع البيانات.
If you need to learn or refresh on these topics,
إذا كنت بحاجة إلى تعلم أو تحديث هذه الموضوعات،
check out the resources and instructor notes below.
فراجع الموارد وملاحظات المعلم أدناه.
In this first lesson,
في هذا الدرس الأول،
you'll learn about the steps of the data analysis process
ستتعرف على خطوات عملية تحليل البيانات
and practice investigating on different data sets along the way.
وممارسة التحقيق في مجموعات البيانات المختلفة على طول الطريق.
In the next two lessons,
في الدرسين التاليين،
you will complete case studies while you perform
ستكمل دراسات الحالة أثناء إجراء عملية
the entire data analysis process on two data sets. Let's get started.
تحليل البيانات بالكامل على مجموعتي بيانات. لنبدأ.